Thank you.
I don't need one.
I got a good phone.
Good morning.
It took a minute to get the roll going this morning.
Okay.
I got it over here, but I'm going to need to put these on the way.
This is out of the stash and accompanies those extra ones.
Okay.
Does he have the sparring?
Yes.
.
Thank you.
man frigid so should i start with one of these guys yeah yeah yeah start with
yeah six and it's going to have a little i didn't take these
and then what i was interested in is open that one up where the game control is where the batteries
are let's see where that one's set yeah this one's set almost at full you see a little arrow
It's like one o'clock.
Okay, I see this comes out back a little bit.
Okay.
Just go back to the scene.
Should we do that for the rest of the room?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just one o'clock.
Yeah.
Just so we're at the same reference.
Take all of the, all of the, for lack of a better word,
because it ties up here.
Okay.
Set it over there.
That is what this little squishy comes in.
If you don't want to use the squishy, you can put it in there to keep it nice.
This helps when someone says the letter P or T.
It doesn't make that popping sound through the microphone.
That little piece of phone does that.
Yeah.
complosives.
Consensibles.
That's a good question.
Sophia's full of them.
All bad?
Oh, yeah.
Good questions.
They're good.
She's 50% good questions, 50% attitude.
Okay, well, that's okay, too, as long as it's focused correctly.
It will be.
I'm Michael by the way, Sophia right?
Hi Michael.
Hello, I'm Michael.
Okay.
Let's start with six.
Let me just see.
So I can just turn it on.
Can I just push it?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Test.
Test one, two.
Hello?
Testing one, two.
Test one two.
Hang on.
Testing one two.
Enna, vio.
One two.
Test one two.
Enna.
Okay.
Let's see here.
Oh
Τότε κάτι ήλθες προς τον θάνατον η ζωή αθάνατος, τότε τον άδεινε νέκρος σας,
η άστραπη της θεότητος, τότε δε και του στεθνεώτας εκ των κατακθονίων ανέστησας.
Πάσε δυνάμι στον επουρανή
Μπορείς άλλη λίγο.
Okay.
Test 1-2
Do you want me to
I'll just chant
Okay
The Holy Spirit is the Holy Spirit, the Holy Spirit is the Holy Spirit.
ο ερχόμενος εν ονόματι Κυρίου.
Θεός Κυρίος και επεφάνεν ημιν ευλογημένος
Των λίθων του μνήματος φράγι στην εμικολύσσας
Την πέτρα αντίθεση
7-8.
Μετά το πάθος πορεύθησε εν το μνήματι, προς το μυρίσε το σώμα σου, εγινέκες Χριστέ ο Θεός,
Είδω να γένουσεν το τάφο και εξέστησαν φωνείς γαρίκου ορακού.
εξ αυτών ότι άνεστη ο Κύριος.
Εν το ουράνο τα ώματα εκπέμπω μου της καρδίας προς σε σωτήρ σ' όσον με ση επιλάμψη,
ελέησον ημάς τους πτέοντας η πόλα, κάθε κά στην ουραν ο Χριστέ μου,
και δώσ' προτελούς τρόπους του μετανοήνση,
πόξα πατρίδινση.
και Υιώ και Αγίου.
Σαρτά από τον Άμιν.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιώ και Αγίου Πνεύματι,
και νυν και αϊκέ εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων,
Αγίοι ο Πνεύματι το βασιλεύει
Αγίοι ο Πνεύματι το βασιλεύειν πέλη, το αγιάζειν το κοινήν την κτίσην,
Θεός γαρέστην, όμως ή ως πατρή και λόγο.
Υμοι ότι κύριος είναι ημιν της ικανός ο
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Hello.
Αυτό.
Ο Θεός ειλάσθητη με το αμαρτωλό κελέησον με.
Ευλογητός ο Θεός ημών πάντοτε εν ίνθω.
Αμήν.
Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος Ισχυρός, Άγιος Αθάνατος, ελέησον ημάς
Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος Ισχυρός, Άγιος Αθάνατος, ελέησον ημάς.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιό και Αγίο Πνεύματι, και νυν και αΐ και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν.
Παναγία Τριάς, ελέησον ημάς.
Κύριε ηλάσθη διδεσαι αμαρτίες ημών, δέσποτα συγχώρησον τα σανομία σιμήν.
Άγιοι επίσκεψε και ίασε τα σασθενεία σιμών
Ένεκεν του όνοματός σου
Κύριε Λέισον, Κύριε Λέισον
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αλλά ρίσσε ημάς από του πονηρού.
Ό,τι σου εστίνει η Βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα
του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Αγίου Πνεύματος
νυν και αι και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν. Σώσον Κύριε των λαών σου και ευλόγισον την πληρονομίαν σου.
Νίκας της βασιλεύσης κατά βαρβάρων δουρούμενος
και τοσών φυλάτων δια του σταυρού σου πολίτευμα.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιόγειο.
και Αγίο Πνεύματι, ο υψωθής εν το σταυρό
εκουσίως, τη επωνύμου σου καινή πολιτεία
του συκτηρμού σου τόρισε Χριστέ ο Θεός
έφρανον εν τη δυνάμι σου τους πιστούς βασιλείς ημών
νίκας χορηγών αυτής κατά των πολεμίων
την συμμαχίαν έχει εν την συν όπλων ειρήνης
αείτη των τρόπαιων και νίν και αεί και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων
αμήν. Προστασία φοβερά και άκατέσκυνται
μη παρήδεις γαθήτας και ασίασημων
Πανείμνητε Θεοτόκε, στήριξε Ορθοδόξων Πολιτείαν, σώζε...
Have mercy on us, O God, according to your great mercy.
We pray to you, hear us and have mercy.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Let us pray for pious and orthodox Christians.
Again we pray for our Father and Archbishop Nick.
Nicholas, and all our brotherhood in Christ.
For you are a merciful God who loves mankind,
and to you we offer up glory,
to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit,
now and forever, and to the ages of ages.
Amen. In the name of the Lord, Father, bless.
Glory to the holy, consubstantial life-giving,
an undivided Trinity always.
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Glory to God in the highest
and on earth peace goodwill among men.
O Lord, you shall open my lips
and my mouth will declare your praise.
O Lord, why do those who afflict me multiply?
Many are those who rise up against me.
Many are those who say to my soul, there is no salvation for him and his God.
But you, O Lord, are my protector, my glory, and the one who lifts up my head.
I cried to the Lord with my voice, and he heard me from his holy hill.
I lay down and slept. I awoke, for the Lord will help me.
I will not be afraid of ten thousands of people who set themselves against me all around.
Arise, O Lord, and save me, O my God, for you struck all those who were foolishly at enmity with me.
You broke the teeth of sinners. Salvation is of the Lord, and your blessing is upon your people.
I lay down and slept, I awoke, for the Lord will help me.
O Lord, do not rebuke me in your wrath, nor chasten me in your anger.
For your arrows are fixed in me, and your hand rests on me.
There is no healing in my flesh because of your wrath.
There is no peace in my bones because of my sins.
For my transgressions rise up over my head.
Like a heavy burden, they are heavy on me.
My wounds grow foul and fester because of my folly.
I suffer misery. I am utterly bowed down.
I go all the day long with a sad face.
for my loins are filled with mockeries
and there is no healing in my flesh.
I am afflicted and greatly humbled.
I roar because of the groaning of my heart.
O Lord, all my desire is before you,
and my groaning is not hidden from you.
My heart is troubled, my strength fails me,
and the light of my eyes, even this is not with me.
My friends and neighbors draw near and stand against me,
and my near of kin stand far off.
And those who seek my soul use violence,
and those who seek evil for me speak folly,
and they meditate on deceit all the day long.
But I, like a deaf man, do not hear,
and I am like a mute who does not
He says,
love as though it were a stinking corpse. Do not forsake me, O Lord, my God. Do not depart from me.
Give heed to help me, O Lord, of my salvation. Do not forsake me, O Lord, O my God. Do not depart
from me. Give heed to help me, O Lord, of my salvation. O God, my God, I rise early to be with
you. My soul thirsts for you. How often my flesh thirsts for you in a desolate, impassable, and
waterless land. So in the holy place I appear before you to see your power and your glory.
because your mercy is better than life.
My lips shall praise you.
Thus I will bless you in my life. I will lift up my hands in your name.
May my soul be filled as with marrow and fatness,
and my mouth shall sing praise to you with lips filled with rejoicing.
If I remembered you on my bed, I meditated on you at daybreak,
for you are my helper, and in the shelter of your wings I will greatly rejoice.
My soul follows close behind you, and your right hand takes hold of me.
But they seek for my soul in vain.
They shall go into the lowest parts of the earth.
They shall be given over to the edge of the sword.
They shall be a portion for foxes.
but the king
shall be glad in God. All who swear by him shall be praised, for the mouth that speaks unrighteous
things is stopped. I meditated on you at daybreak, for you are my helper, and in the shelter of your
wings I will greatly rejoice. My soul follows close behind you, your right hand takes hold of me.
Glory to the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, both now and ever, and to the ages of ages.
Amen. Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia, glory to you, O God. Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia, glory to you,
O God. Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia, glory to you, O God. Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy,
you, Lord.
mercy, glory to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit, both now and ever into the
ages of ages. Amen. O Lord, God of my salvation, I cry day and night before you. Let my prayer
come before you, incline your ear to my supplication, O Lord. For my soul is filled with sorrows
and my soul draws near to Hades. I am counted among those who go down into the pit. I am
like a helpless man, free among the dead, like slain men thrown down and sleeping in
a grave, whom you remember no more, but they are removed from your hand. They laid me in
the lowest pit in dark
places and in the shadow of death. Your wrath rested upon me and you brought all your billows
over me. You removed my acquaintances far from me. They made me an abomination among themselves.
I was betrayed and did not go forth. My eyes weakened from poverty, O Lord. I cried to you
the whole day. I spread out my hands to you. Will you work wonders for the dead? Or will physicians
raise them up and acknowledge you? Shall anyone in the grave describe your mercy and your truth
and destruction? Shall your wonders be known in darkness and your righteousness in a forgotten
But I cried to you, O Lord, and in the morning my parishioners
come near to you. Why, O Lord, do you reject
my soul and turn away your face for me?
I am poor and in troubles for my youth,
but having been exalted, I was humbled
and brought into despair. Your fierce
anger passed over me, and your terrors greatly
troubled me. They compassed me like water
all the day long. They surrounded
me at once. You removed far from
me neighbor and friend and my acquaintances
because of my misery. O Lord, God
of my salvation, I cry day and night before you.
Let my prayer come before you and climb
your ear to my supplication, O Lord.
Bless the Lord, O my soul, and everything within me.
bless his holy name. Bless the Lord, O my soul, and forget not all his rewards, who is merciful to all
your transgressions, who heals all your diseases, who redeems your life from corruption, who crowns
you with mercy and compassion, who satisfies your desire with good things, and your youth is renewed
like the eagles. The Lord shows mercies and judgments to all who are wronged. He made known
his ways to Moses and the things that he willed to the sons of Israel. The Lord is compassionate and
merciful, slow to anger, and abounding in mercy. He will not become angry to the end.
nor will he be wrathful forever.
He did not deal with us according to our sins,
nor reward us according to our transgressions.
For according to the height of heaven from earth,
so the Lord reigns in mercy over those who fear him.
As far as the east is from the west,
so he removes our transgressions from us.
As a father has compassion on his children,
so the Lord has compassion on those who go in fear of him.
For he knows how he formed us, he remembers we are dust.
Man, his days are like grass, as a flower of the field,
so he flourishes.
for the wind passes through it.
and it shall not remain, and it shall no longer know its place.
But the mercy of the Lord is from age to age upon those who fear him,
and his righteousness upon children's children,
to such as keep his covenant and remember his commandments to do them.
The Lord prepared his throne in heaven, and his kingdom rules over all.
Bless the Lord, all you his angels, mighty in strength, who do his word,
so as to hear the voice of his words.
Bless the Lord, all you his hosts, his ministers who do his will.
Bless the Lord, all his works, in all places of his dominion.
and bless the Lord, O my soul.
all places of his dominion. Bless the Lord, O my soul. O Lord, hear my prayer. Give ear to my
supplication in your truth. Answer me in your righteousness, and do not enter into judgment
with your servant, for no one living shall become righteous in your sight. For the enemy persecuted
my soul. He humbled my life to the ground. He caused me to dwell in dark places as one long dead,
and my spirit was in anguish within me. My heart was troubled within me. I remembered the days of
old. I meditated on all your works. I meditated on the works of your hands. I spread out my
hand.
to you. My soul thirsts for you like a waterless land. Hear me speedily, O Lord. My spirit faints
within me. Turn not your face from me, lest I become like those who go down into the pit.
Cause me to hear your mercy in the morning, for I hope in you. Make me know, O Lord, the way wherein
I should walk, for I lift up my soul to you. Deliver me from my enemies, O Lord, for to you I flee for
refuge. Teach me to do your will, for you are my God. Your good spirit shall guide me in the land
of uprightness. For your name's sake, O Lord, give me life. In your righteousness you shall bring my
soul out of affliction.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Doxasio, Theos, Elbis, Simon, Kyrie, doxasio.
In peace, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For the peace of God and the salvation of our souls,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For peace in the whole world,
for the stability of the holy churches of God,
and for the unity of all, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For this holy house and for those who enter it,
with faith, reverence, and the fear of God,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our Father and Archbishop Nicholas,
the Honourable Presbyters,
the deacons in the service of Christ,
and all the clergy and people,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our country, the President,
and all those in public service,
Thank you.
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For this parish and city,
for every city and country,
and for the faithful who live in them,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For favorable weather and abundance
of the fruits of the earth
and for peaceful times,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For travelers by land, sea and air,
for the sick, the suffering,
index
captives and for their
salvation. Let us
pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our deliverance from
all affliction, wrath, danger,
and distress, let us pray
to the Lord. Lord, have
mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy
on us, and protect us, O God,
by your grace. Amen.
Remembering
our most holy, pure, blessed,
and glorious Lady, the Theodok
I'm so glad to be here.
and ever-Virgin Mary with all the saints,
let us commit ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
For to you belong all glory, honor, and worship
to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
God is the Lord and...
He revealed Himself to us.
Blessed is He who comes in the name of the Lord.
All the nations surround us.
But in the name of the Lord I defended myself against them.
God is the Lord and He revealed Himself to us.
Blessed is He who comes in the name of the Lord.
When you descended unto death, O Lord, you who are immortal life,
put Hades to death by the lightning of your divinity.
And when you raised the dead from the netherworld,
all the hosts of heaven sang aloud to you,
O Christ, God, giver of life, glory to you.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιό και Άγιο Πνεύματι, ότε κατήρθες προς τον θάνατον, η ζωή αθάνατος, τότε τον άδεινε νέκρος σας, τη άστραπη της θεότητος,
Ότε δε και τους τεθνεώτας εκ των κατακθονίων ανέστησας, πάσε δυναμή.
εις τον επουρανίον, εγκράβγαζον, ζώδωτα Χριστέ ο Θεός ημών, δόξα Συν.
Και νυν και αΐ και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων, αμήν,
εν πίστη τους προπάτορας, εδικαίωσας,
την εξεθνών δι' αυτών προμνηστευσάμενος εκκλησίαν.
καυχόντε εν δόξη Άγιοι
ότι εξ πέρμαντος αυτών υπάρχει καρπός ευκλαιής, η ασπόρος θεκούσασε,
τε σ' αυτών η και εσύ εσχριστέ ο Θεός, σώσοντας ψυχάσιμο.
ΑΕΤΙ ΚΕΤΗ ΕΝ ΕΝΗΝΗ Του Κύριου ΔΕΙΘΟΜΕΡΙΗΣΟΝ
ΑΝτιλαβούς όσων ελέησων και διαφυλαξον ημάς
ο Θεός της ηχάριτης,
Κύριε Λέησον,
της Παναγίας Αχράτου,
υπερευλογημένης ενδόξου,
δεσποινήσιμον Θεοτόκου,
και αϊπαρθένου Μαρίας,
μεταπάντων των Αγίων
γημονεύσαντες,
εαυτούς και αλλήλους
και πάσα την ζωήν ημών,
Χριστό το Θεό
παραθώμεθα.
Συγκύριε
Ο της Σοντοκράτος και σου έστειν η Βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Αγίου Πνεύματος νυν και αη και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν, ο Εύσχημον Ιωσήφ από του ξύλου καθελόν του άχραντών σου σώμα.
Συνδώνει καθαρά η λύστας και αρώμασιν, ενήματι και νόκυδεύσας απέθετο,
αλλά τριήμερος ανέστης Κύριε παρέχον το κόσμο το μεγαέλαιο.
Δόξα Πατρή και Υωκή Αγιοπνεύματι τες μυροφόρης γυνέξη παρά το μνήμα επιστά.
ο άγγελος ευώα, τα μοίρα της θνητής υπάρχει αρμόδια,
Χριστός δε διαφθόρας εδείχθη αλότριος,
αλλά κραυγάσατε ανέστη ο Κύριος, παρέχον το κόσμο το μεγαέλαιος.
Και νυν και αοικαίοι στους αιώνας των αιώνων, αμήν.
Πάντα υπερένειαν, πάντα υπερένδοξα τας αθεότο και μυστήρια,
η αγνία εσφραγισμένη και παρθενή αφυλατωμένη,
μη τήρε γνώστης αψεύδης θεών τεκούς αληθινών,
αυτόν η κέτευε σωθήν εντάς ψυχάσιμο.
Των λιθών του μνήματος φραγμένου
Αγίστην εμικολύσας, την πέτρα της πίστεως,
Αναστάς παρέσκη πάσης, Κύριε, δόξα Σύ.
Ωξα Πατρί και Υιώ και Αγίω Πνεύματι,
Τον μαθητών Σου ο χώρος συν μυροφόρης γίνεξε,
Να γάλετε συμφώνος, κινήν γαρεορτήν Συν αυτή σε ορτάζου,
εις δόξαν και τιμήν της εις αναστάσεως,
και δι' αυτόν φιλάνθρωπε Κύριε,
το λαό σου παράσκου το μεγαέλαιο.
Και νυν και αοικέεις τους αιώνας των αιώνων,
αμήν υπερευλογημένη υπάρχεις Θεοτό και παρθένε,
Διαγάρτου εξούς αρκωμένου
ο θέντος, ο άδης ηχμαλώτης ται, ο αδάμ ανάκαι κλητέ, η κατάραν νεκροτέ, η ευαϊνλευθέρωτε, ο θάνατος ται θανάτοτε,
και ημίσες ζωποιήθημεν δύο ανυμνούντες βόμεν ευλογητός Χριστός ο Θεός ημών
ο ούτως ευδοκής σας δόξα σύν.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδαξόν με τα δικαίωματά σου,
τον αγγέλων ο Δήμος κατεπλάγι ορών σε,
ενεκρής λογηστέντα του θάνατου δε σωτήρ την ισχύν καθελώντα,
και σ' ειναι αυτόν τον Αδά με Γύραντα
Εξάδου πάντας ελευθερός αντά.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδάξον με τα δικαιώματά σου,
τι τα μοίρας ημπαθος της δάκρυσην, ο μαθητριε κυρνάται,
ο αστράπτον εν το τάφο άγγελος προσευθέν και τότε σμυροφόρης.
Είδετε, είμείς των τάφων και είσθητε, ως ότι είστε.
Ρεξανέστη του μνήματον.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδαξον με τα δικαιωμάτα σου λείαν.
Πρωί μυροφόριε δραμον προς το μνήμα σου θρηνολογούσε.
Αλέπες τι προς αυτός ο άγγελος και είπε,
Τρινού ο καιρός π' αυτε μη πλέτε την Ανάσταση δε αποστολή.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κύριε.
Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Δόξα σύ ο Θεός.
ΑΕΤΙΚΕΤΕΤΕΝ ΕΕΡΗΝΗ ΤΗ ΚΥΡΙΟ ΔΕΙΘΟΜΕΝ
ΚΥΡΙΗ ΕΛΕΙΣΟΝ
Σας ευχαριστώ.
Αυτός και λύλος και πάσαν την ζωήν ημών Χριστό το Θεό παραθώ μεθά.
Συ Κύριε.
Ότι ευλογητέ σου το όνομα και το δοξαστέ σου η Βασιλεία του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Άγιου Πνεύματος,
νυν και αϊκέις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν.
Μετά το πάθος πορευθείσαι εν το μνήματι, προς το μυρίσε το σώμα σου, εγυναίκες Χριστέ ο Θεός.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Είδω να γγέλουσεν το τάφο και εξέστησαν φωνείς γαρίκουον εξ αυτών, ότι ανέστη ο Κύριος παρέχον το κόσμο το μέγα έλεος.
Εν το ουρανό τα ώματα εκπέμπω μου της καρδίας προς εσωτείρους όσον με ση επιλάμψει.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κι δώς προς θέλους τρόπους του μετανοήν Σοι.
Φόξα Πατρί και Υό και Άγιο Πνεύματι.
Δίν και Άγιο και Ιστους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν.
Άγιο Πνεύματι το βασιλεύειν πέλη το Άγι Άζιν το Κινήν την κτίσην Θεός γαρεστήν,
ο Μαούσιος πατρί και λόγο
γυμιώτη Κύριος η Λόγωνα
Είναιν ημήν θυσικανός ως φυλακτήνε, εκ του εχθρού άμα και ανθρώποκτονου.
Ισοδούς ειν αυτόν μη παραδώσο τερ των σονβούλων, λέοντος τρόπον,
κατέ μου κινούνται και γάρι εχθροί μου.
Ω ξαπαδρή και ιό και Άγιο Πνεύματι,
και είν και αεί και εις τους αιώνας των αιών,
Αγίω πνευματίζω αρχή, χία και γέρας πάντα γάρτα κτιστά,
ως Θεός ον δύναμη συντηρεί εν πατρίδι ουδέ.
Υπεπιθώτες επί Κύριον, εήκα συνόρι το Αγίο,
Ιουδαμος αλεύονται προσβολές του βελία.
Ενώνομοι εσχύρασοι
Αγίος Αυτόν μη εκτινάτως ανηθίως όντες, ουγάρε α Χριστός τη ράβδο των κλήρων αυτού.
Ω ξαπατρί και Υιώ και Αγίω Πνεύματι και την Θεά η καίης τους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν.
Καίοι ο Πνεύματι προσπηγάζει πάσα σοφία, ενθεν χάρις Αποστόλης και της άθλης κατάστασης.
τα στέφονται μάρτυρες και προφήται ορόσι.
Εξεγέρθητη Κύριε ο Θεός μου, εν προστάγματιό εν αιτήλο, και συναγωγή λαόν κυκλώσησε.
Again and again in peace let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us,
and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
Remembering our most holy, pure, blessed, and glorious
Lady Theothokos and ever-Virgin Mary
with all the saints,
let us commend ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
To you, O Lord.
For you are the King of peace and Saviour of our souls,
and to you we offer glory.
Glory to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and unto the ages of ages.
Amen.
Worshiping not the image made by hands,
but putting on the breastplate of the unwritten essence,
in the arena of fire you thrice-blessed ones were glorified.
Standing in the midst of a flame unendurable,
you called upon God.
Make haste, O compassionate one, and hurry as the merciful one unto our aid,
for you can do what you will.
Extend your hand, which of old the Egyptians, making battle,
and the Hebrews, then embattled, had experienced.
Do not forsake us, that death, who thirsts after us,
and Satan, who hates us, may drink us down.
But be near us and spare our souls, as you once spared your lads in Babylon,
as they see
ceaselessly sang your praises,
and were for you thrown into the furnace,
and from thence called to you.
Make haste, O compassionate one,
and hurry as the merciful one unto our aid.
For you can do what you will.
On the 14th of this month,
we commemorate the contest of the holy martyrs
Thyrsus, Lucius, and Kalinicus.
On this day, we commemorate the holy martyrs
Thank you.
Philemon, Apollyonos, Arianos, and those with them.
On this day we also commemorate the four guards
who contested together with Arianos.
On this day we also commemorate the great love
which was shown to us when we were delivered
from the fearful threat of earthquake by our benevolent Lord.
Today is also the Sunday of the Holy Forefathers.
By the intercessions of your saints, O God,
have mercy on us and save us. Amen.
Ananis.
Christ is born, glorify Him.
Christ is come from heaven, go and meet Him.
Christ is on earth, arise to Him.
Sing to the Lord, all you inhabitants of the world.
And all you peoples praise him, and with merriment extol him who is glorified.
To the Son begotten from the Father unchangingly before the ages,
and now becoming incarnate from the Virgin without sight.
To Christ God let us cry aloud,
You have exalted the horn of our strength,
Only you are holy, O Lord.
A rod has come forth from Jesse's root,
And you its flower grew from it.
Praiseworthy Christ, now born of the earth.
whom Habakkuk called Paran,
shady, thickly wooded mountain,
from her who knew no man you came incarnate.
O immaterial God, glory to your strength, O Lord.
O God of peace and Father of mercies,
You have sent.
to us the wonderful Counselor,
the angel of your great counsel,
granting us peace.
And now to light of knowledge
of God we have been guided,
and we rise from night to dawn
and glorify you, O benevolent Lord.
Lord.
Jonah long ago was hurled from the belly of the whale,
as he went in like a newborn babe with the virgin now,
when the logos had dwelt in his mother's womb.
Taking flesh, he then emerged, preserving her intact,
yielding not to a chance.
In changeability, he preserved her unaltered in childbirth.
Brought up together piously the servants,
With contempt regarded the impious king's decree.
The threat of the furnace did not frighten them,
Rather standing in the middle of the church.
midst of the flames they prayed and sang,
Blessed are you, O Lord God of our fathers.
We praise and we bless and we worship the Lord.
Babylon's bedoing furnace bore the image
of an extraordinary wonder.
For it did not burn the youths it was holding,
nor did the fire of divinity
consume the virgin's womb wherein it went.
And so let us songfully extol and praise.
Let all creation bless the Lord, sing I him to him,
and exalt him beyond man.
unto all the ages.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For you, our God, are holy,
and you rest among the holy ones.
And to you we offer up glory
to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever.
you
And to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Let everything that breathes praise the Lord.
Pass up no ienesatot on Kyrian.
Let us pray to the Lord our God that we may be made worthy to hear the holy gospel.
Lord, have mercy, Lord.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Wisdom arise, let us hear the Holy Gospel.
Peace be with you all.
And with your spirit.
The reading is from the Holy Gospel according to Luke.
Wisdom, let us be attentive.
Glory to you, O Lord, glory to you.
At that time, two of them were going to a village.
named Emmaus about seven miles from Jerusalem
and talking with each other
about all these things that had happened.
While they were talking and discussing together,
Jesus himself drew near and went with them.
But their eyes were kept from recognizing him,
and he said to them,
What is this conversation
which you are holding with each other as you walk?
And they stood still, looking sad.
Then one of them named Cleopas answered him,
Are you the only visitor to Jerusalem
who does not know
the things that have happened there in these days? And he said to them, What things? And they said to
him, Concerning Jesus of Nazareth, who was a prophet mighty in deed and word before God and all the
people, and how our chief priests and rulers delivered him up to be condemned to death and
crucified him. But we had hoped that he was the one to redeem Israel. Yes, and besides all this,
it is now the third day since this happened. Moreover, some women of our company amazed us.
they were
were at the tomb early in the morning and did not find his body. And they came back saying that they
had even seen a vision of angels who said that he was alive. Some of those who were with us went to
the tomb and found it just as the women had said, but him they did not see. And he said to them,
O foolish men and slow of heart to believe all that the prophets have spoken, was it not necessary
that the Christ should suffer these things
and enter into his glory?
And beginning with...
Moses and all the prophets, he interpreted to them and all the scriptures the things concerning
himself. So they drew near to the village to which they were going. He appeared to be going further,
but they constrained him, saying, Stay with us, for it is toward evening, and the day is now far
spent. So he went in to stay with them. When he was at table with them, he took the bread and
blessed and broken and gave it to them. And their eyes were opened, and they recognized him, and he
vanished out.
of their sight. They said to each other, Did not our hearts burn within us while he spoke to us on
the road, while he opened to us the scriptures? And they rose that same hour and returned to
Jerusalem, and they found the eleven gathered together, and those who were with them who said,
The Lord has risen indeed and has appeared to Simon. Then they told what had happened on the road.
and he was known to them in the breaking of the bread.
Glory to you, O Lord, glory to you.
Having beheld the resurrection of Christ,
let us worship the Holy Lord Jesus, the only sinless one.
Your cross, O Christ, we venerate,
and your holy resurrection we praise.
and glorify. For you are our God.
Apart from you we know no other.
We call upon your name. Come,
all faithful, let us venerate the
holy resurrection of Christ. For behold,
through the cross, joy has come to the whole
world. Ever blessing the Lord, let
us praise his resurrection. For having
endured the cross for us, he destroyed
death by death.
Have mercy on me, O God,
according to your great mercy
and according to the
abundance of your compassion.
Lord, not my transgression.
Wash me thoroughly from my lawlessness and cleanse me from my sin.
For I know my lawlessness and my sin is always before me.
Against you only have I sinned and done evil in your sight,
that you may be justified in your words.
And overcome when you are judged, for behold,
I was conceived in transgressions and in sin
my mother bore me.
Behold, you love truth.
You showed me the unknown and secret things of your wisdom.
You shall sprinkle me with hyssop and I will be cleansed.
You shall wash me and I will be made whiter than snow.
You shall make me hear joy and gladness.
My bones that were humbled shall greatly rejoice.
Turn your face from my sins
and blot out all my transgressions.
Create in me a clean heart, O God,
and renew a right spirit within me.
Do not cast me away from your presence
and do not take your Holy Spirit from me.
Restore me to the joy of your salvation
and uphold me with your guiding spirit.
I will teach transgressors your ways
and the ungodly shall turn back to you.
Deliver me from blood guiltiness.
O God, the God of my salvation, and my tongue shall greatly rejoice in your righteousness.
O Lord, you shall open my lips, and my mouth will declare your praise.
For if you desired sacrifice, I would give it.
You will not be pleased with whole burnt offerings.
A sacrifice to God is a broken spirit, a broken and humbled heart.
God will not despise
Do good, O Lord, in your good pleasure
Let the walls of Jerusalem be built.
Then you will be pleased with a sacrifice of righteousness,
with offerings and whole burnt offerings.
Then shall they offer young bulls on your altar
and have mercy on me, O God.
Glory to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
at the intercession of the...
apostles, O Lord of mercy, blot out my many offenses, both now and ever and to the ages
of ages.
Amen.
At the intercession of the Theotokos, O Lord of mercy, blot out my many offenses.
have mercy on me O God
according to your great mercy
according to the abundance of your compassion, blot out my transgression.
Jesus, having risen from the grave as he foretold, has granted us eternal life and great mercy.
He.
O God, save your people and bless your inheritance.
Look upon your world with mercy and compassion.
Raise the Orthodox Christians in glory
and send down upon us your rich mercies.
Through the intercessions of our all-immaculate Lady Theotokos,
an ever-virgin Mary,
by the power of the precious and life-giving cross,
the protection of the honorable heavenly bodiless powers,
the supplications of the honourable, glorious Prophet
and forerunner John the Baptist,
the holy, glorious, and praiseworthy apostles,
our fathers among the saints,
the great hierarchs and ecumenical teachers,
Basil the Great, Gregory the Theologian,
and John Chrysostom,
Athanasius, Cyril, and John the Merciful,
Patriarchs of Alexandria,
Nicholas, Bishop of Myra,
Spyridon, Bishop of Trimithus,
Nectarios of Pendapolis,
the Wonder Workers,
the holy glory
the glorious great martyrs, George the Triumphant,
Demetrius the Merced Dreamer, Theodore the Soldier,
Theodore the General, Minas the Wonder Worker,
Haralumbos and Elephterios, the holy priest martyrs,
the holy glorious and victorious martyrs,
the glorious great martyr and all audible Ephemia,
the holy and glorious martyrs, Thecla Barbara,
Anastasia Catherine, Kyriakie,
Fautini, Marina, Parasitia,
our venerable and God-bearing fathers,
the holy and righteous ancestors of God,
Joachim and Anna, and the holy forefathers
whose memory we observe, and all your saints.
We beseech you, only merciful Lord,
hear us, sinners who pray to you,
and have mercy on us.
Kyrie eleison, Kyrie eleison, Kyrie eleison,
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Lord, have mercy.
Kyrie eleison, kyrie eleison, kyrie eleison.
Through the mercies, compassion, and love for humankind
of your only begotten Son, with whom you are blessed,
and your all-holy good.
και τη ζωή που βοηθούν τον Φωτός, τώρα και για μένα και στις ώρες των ώρων.
Την Θεοτόκον και Μητέρα του Φωτός, εν ύμνης τιμώντες μεγαλύνομαι.
Μεγαλύνει η ψυχή μου τον Κύριον και η γαλλία σε το Πνεύμα μου,
επί το Θεό το σωτήρι μου
For he has regarded the lowly state of his maidservant.
For behold, henceforth all generations will call me blessed.
greater in honor than thou.
The Cherubim, and in glory greater be uncompared than the Seraphim,
you without corruption gave birth to God the Word,
and our truly Theotokos, you do we magnify.
O die epi se me megalia o dynatos k agion t' o noma aftou,
k e to e leos aftou is gennean k e gennean dis fovoumenis aftou,
and I will be the most proud of my dear
He has shown strength with his arm, he has scattered the proud
in the imagination of their hearts, greater in honor than the cherubim
and in glory greater beyond compare than the seraphim.
You without corruption gave birth to God the Word and are truly the Otochos, you do we magnify.
!
sin gritos ton seraphim,
in a diaforos
theon logon tecusan,
in ondos theotokon
se megalinomen.
He has helped his servant Israel
in remembrance of his mercy
as he spoke to our fathers,
to Abraham and to his seed forever.
Greater in honor than the cherubim
and in glory.
greater beyond compare than the seraphim.
You without corruption gave birth to God the Word, and are truly
theotokos, you do we magnify.
O my soul, magnify the
woman who is higher in honor
and in glory than the honor
I see here a new and paradoxical mystery, for the cave resembles heaven, the virgin, the cherubic throne, the manger, a grand space.
in which he whom nothing can contain was alone.
Christ our God, whom we extol in song and magnify.
ο Θεός της ηχάρητης
της Παναγίας Αχράτου υπερευλογημένης εν δόξου
δεσπίνησήμων Θεοτόκου και αϊπαρθένου Μαρίας
με τα πάντων των Αγίων μνημονεύσαντες
εαυτούς και αλλήλους και πάσαν την ζωήν ημών
Χριστό το Θεό παραθώ μεθά
Συν Κύριε
Πάσε δυνάμεις των ουρανών και εσύ την δόξα αναπέμπωση.
Το πατρί και το Υίο και το Άγιο Πνεύμα θυ νυν και αη και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν, Άγιος Κύριος ο Θεός ημών,
Όλοι εστά λόρδι αργάρ,
Υψούτε Κύριον των Θεών ημών και προς το Ιωσί.
κινείται το υποποδείο των ποδών αυτού,
ότι αγιώς αισθεί.
When Christ, the way, the true, the life,
rose from the dead, He drew near,
and went with Luke and Cleopas to Emmaus and broke bread,
and with that they recognized Him,
their souls and hearts within them had birthed.
while he had talked to them on the road
and had interpreted to them.
In all the scriptures, the things he had suffered,
with them we shout, the Lord arose,
and he appeared to Peter.
Come, all who love our ancestors
and duty-bound exultantly,
let us assemble and honor
more.
the memory of the fathers, Jacob, Isaac, and Abraham,
from whom descended Christ the Lord
when he became incarnate in his abundant compassion.
O faithful, let us sing in praise of Adam, Abel, and of Seth,
of Enos and Enoch and Noah,
of Abraham and
And of Isaac and Jacob, Moses and of Job and Aaron and Eliezer,
of Joshua and of Barak, of Samson and of Jephthah, of Solomon and of David.
O Virgin, pure, immaculate, all-holy Mary, bride of God,
in that frightening hour.
Stand before us.
for me the lowly
and mediate with
your own Son.
And thus I pray deliver
me from final
condemnation
and punishments
of
perdition.
Nepas
up
no
him
Εν εσάτω τον Κύριον, εν είτε τον Κύριον εκ των ουρανών,
εν είτε αυτών εν της ύψης της,
σοι πρέπει ημνοστό.
Ω Θεό, εν είτε αυτών πάντες οι άγγελοι αυτού,
Σου εν η θέαυτων πάσε, ε δυνάμεις αυτούν.
Συ πρέπει.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Praise God and His saints.
Praise Him in the firmament of His power.
Let the Jewish leaders explain it.
How did the soldiers lose the king whom they were guarding?
Why couldn't the stone secure the rock of life?
Either produce him who was buried,
or else worship him as risen from the dead.
the
Join us and say glory to the abundance of your tender mercies.
Our Savior, glory to you.
.
αυτού.
Χαίρεται λαοί και αγάλη άστε, άγγελος σε κάθισεν εις των λίθων του μνημάτος,
αυτός ημάς ευγγελίσατο.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
of the world
and filled
the messages
of the
praise him
with the
sound of
trumpet
praise him
with the
harp
and the
lyre
before
your
conception
I'm sorry.
an angel brought the salutation.
Rejoice to the maiden full of grace
again at your resurrection.
An angel rolled away the stone
from your glorious tomb, O Lord,
the one brought a prize.
of joy, replacing the pain and sorrow.
The other declared that the Master gives life,
reversing the threat of death.
Therefore we sing to you, Lord and Ben.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Praise Him with resounding symbols.
Praise Him with triumphant symbols.
Let everything that breathes praise the Lord.
Let all of us observe
now the august forefathers' memorial,
extolling their way of life
by virtue of which they have been magnified.
Blessed are you, O Lord, God of our fathers.
For you are praiseworthy and exalted beyond measure unto the ages.
Praising Almighty God, the servants sang in chorus while standing in the furnace,
and thereby they extinguished the force of the engulfing fire.
O ty díkyos ye epiposin, yis episa simin, la gov.
Κατακλειστής, θυρσής συνογισμένος, δανείλο προφήτης, αμετοχός της τούτων, εδείκνει το κακό σε ως.
Θα δόξω παντρικένει
και Αγίο Νευμάτι δευταία πάντες πιστος πανηγύρισομεν
τον πρόνο μου
Πατέρον Αβραάμ και τον Συν
Αυτό την ετσιόν νήμι.
To you that is feeling like sea
O steam is omen
To send Babilonia
Amén.
Συντοδανήλ εφήμισ όμην
Τον προφήτων τας προρίσεις
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Είμαι θυμόνο Θεός.
Υπέρδε δοξασμένη υπάρχεις Θεοτόκε παρθένε
Διαγάρτου έξου σαρκωθέντος
Ως άδης ηχμαλώτης τε, ο Αδάμ ανάκεκλητε, η κατάραν νεκρότε, η Εύα ηλευθέρωτε,
ο θάνατος θε θάνατονται
και ημίσες ομπιθήμεν
διόαν υμνόν
Συγχροντας, ομέν, ευλογητός Χριστός ο Θεός, ο ούτως ευδοκίσας δόξα σοι.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Amen.
Thank you.
For you alone are holy, you alone are Lord Jesus Christ, to the glory of God the Father. Amen.
Every day will I bless you, and I will praise your name forever, and unto the ages of ages.
O Lord, to the Lord.
us this day without sin.
Blessed are you, O Lord, the God of our fathers, and praise and glorify His pure name unto
the ages.
Amen.
Let your mercy, O Lord, be upon us, even when we have hoped in you.
Blessed are you, O Lord Jesus.
I said, O Lord, have mercy on me.
You, my son.
for I have sinned against you.
O Lord, to you have I fled for refuge.
Teach me to do your will, for you are my God.
For in you is the fountain of life.
In your life we shall see lie.
Continue your mercy unto those who are not.
Holy God, holy, mighty, holy, mortal, have mercy on us.
O ye God holy,
O ye immortal, have mercy on us.
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit, both now and ever, and unto
the ages of ages.
Amen.
Holy and mortal have mercy.
Holy God,
Holy
Oh
Immortal, have mercy on us.
Σήμερον σωτηρία το κόσμο γεγονέων σου με το αναστάθι εκτράφου και αρχηγό της ζωής υμών
καθελών γαρμών θανάτων των θάνατων, των οικοσέδων και νήμιν και το μεγαέλαιο.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αμήν
Υπέρ της άνωθεν ειρήνης και της σωτηρίας των ψυχώνημων του Κυρίου Δεηθώμες.
Κύριε Δεηθώμες.
Υπέρ της ειρήνης του σημαντός κόσμου ευσταθίας των Αγίων του Θεού Εκκλησιών
και της των πάντων ενώσεως του Κυρίου Δεηθώμες.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Υπέρ του Αγίου Υφού Του και των μεταπίστεων σε βλαβιάς και φόβου Θεό Ισιοντών εν Αυτόν του Κυρίου Ρεϊθώμεν.
Κύριε θέλευ εισόν
Πέραν των ευσεβών και ορθοδόξων χριστιανών
Κύριου δε ηθόμεν
Κύριε Ειστον, υπέρ του Αρχιεπισκόπου ήμων Νικολάου,
του τιμίου Πρεστητερίου της Εγκριστώ διακονίας παντών του κλήνου και του λαού,
Σκύριου δε Ιθώμα!
Let us pray.
to the Lord.
Lord have
mercy.
For favorable weather, for an abundance
of the fruits of the earth
and for peaceful times
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord
have mercy.
For those
who travel by land, sea and
air, for the sick,
the suffering, the captives and for
their salvation, let us
Thank you.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our deliverance from all affliction, wrath, danger, and necessity,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy upon us,
Keep us, O God, by your grace
for your have mercy.
Memorating our most holy, pure,
blessed and glorious lady,
the Theodokos and ever, Virgin Mary,
together with all the saints,
with us commend our children,
one another,
and the whole life of Christ our God.
To you, O Lord.
For to you belong, O glory,
honor and worship,
to the Lord.
The Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Bless the Lord, O my soul, and all that is within me. Bless his holy name.
Through the intercessions of the Theodokal Savior, save us.
The Lord has prepared his throne in the heavens, and his kingdom rules over all.
Through the intercessions of the Theodokos, Savior, and the Holy Spirit,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αμήν.
Jacob for his help, whose hope is in the Lord his God.
O Son of God, risen from the dead, save us to sing to you.
Alleluia.
Vasiレύσει Κύριος εις τον αιώνα, ο Θεός σου σιώτης γενεάν και γενεάν.
Sons, sony, masy, ethe.
ο Αναστάσαι πνευρών, ψάνοντας η Αλληλούια.
Βόξα Πατρή και Υιό και Άγιο Πνευματί,
φταίνει και αεί και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν,
ο μονογεννησιος και λόγος του Θεού, αθάνατος υπάρχον.
και καταδεξάμενος διά την ημετρέραν σωτηρία.
Σαρκωθήνε εκ της Αγίας Θεοτόπου
και αηπαρθένου Μαρίας, αγραίτος εν άνθρωπη σας.
Σταυρωθείς σε Χριστέ ο Θεός, θανάτω θανάτω.
Again and again and he's let us pray
to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy upon us
and keep us, O God, for your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
Commemorating our most holy, pure, blessed and glorious
Lady of the Father, all of us in heaven, such in Mary,
together with all the saints, let us commend ourselves
and one another, and our whole life to Christ our God.
Oh, boy.
Amen.
For you are a good and loving God,
and you we give glory
to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Σοφία, ορθή.
Δεκτε προσκυνήσομαι και προσπέσομαι Χριστό.
Ωραία!
Σώσον την μάση για Θεού
Ω Αναστάστα κλεκρόφος
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Εκ των κατακτωνίων ανέστησας,
πάσε δυναμής των επουρανίων,
εκραυγάζων, ζωδότα χριστέ,
ο Θεός ημονδόξα σοι.
Ευχαριστώ.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Εν σπηλαίο έρχεται από τεχεινά του ρίδος.
Χόρευε οικομένη ακούτης θέσσα.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αιώνον Θεόν
Τον Κυρίου να ηθώμεν
Ότι Άγιος ή ο Θεός ημών και ζει την όξανα να πέμπωμεν
το Πατρί και το Αιώ και το Αιώ πνεύμα θήνειν και αιή
και ήσθουσε όλα στον αιώνα.
Amen.
Holy God, Holy Mighty, Holy Immortal,
and
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Chantanatos eleison imas.
Holy God, holy and mighty, holy and mighty.
and mercy on us.
.
Αγίος Αθανάτος, ελέησον ημάς.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
και αηκαιριστου σε όχνας των αιώνον αυγή.
Άγιος Σαθάνατος πελέησον ημάς.
Αμή
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
O Lord, look down from heaven and see,
and visit this vineyard,
which your right hand has plastered.
Agios, Athanah, Ato.
Give it a kiss
All right, Lord, O Lord, look down from heaven and see, and visit this vineyard which your righteous blood has planted.
Oh
Βινάμις, Βινάμις, Άγιος, Άφεός, Άγιος,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Ισύρος, Αγίος, Αθάνατος,
Ελέη σ' όνει μας.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Hear thee as us, God, who steps to be.
Lord, save the pious.
Oh, Lord, save the world.
The highest, the highest.
Kyrie soson tu seps evis.
and here I am.
Bartholomew, the all-holy and ecumenical patriarch, many years.
Cheers.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Nicholas the most revered and God chosen Metropolitan of the Holy Metropolis of Detroit
Our Father and Our Shepherd
Many years
!
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Let us be attentive.
Blessed are you, O Lord, the God of our fathers,
for you are just in all you have done.
Wisdom.
The reading is from St. Paul's 11th.
Let us be attentive.
Brethren, when Christ, who is our life, appears,
then you also will appear with him in glory.
Put to death, therefore, what is earthly in you,
fornication, impurity, passion, evil desire,
and covetousness, which is idolatry.
On account of these, the wrath of God
is coming upon the sons of disobedience.
In these you once walked,
when you lived in them. But now put them all away, anger, wrath, malice, slander, and foul
talk from your mouth. Do not lie to one another, seeing that you have put off the old nature
with its practices and have put on the new nature, which is being renewed in knowledge
after the image of its creator. Here there cannot be Greek nor Jew, circumcised nor
uncircumcised, barbarian, Scythian, slave, free man.
But Christ is all, and in all.
Peace be with you, the reader.
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia.
Wisdom arise, let us hear the holy gospel
Yilinipasi peace be with you all
And to your spirit
The reading is according to
Saint Luke.
Let us be attentive.
Glory to you,
Lord,
glory to you.
The Lord said this
parable.
A man once gave a great
banquet and
invited many.
And at the time
of the banquet, he sent
his servant to say to
those who had been invited, Come for all is now ready.
But they all alike began to make excuses.
The first said to him, I have bought a field, and I go out and see it, I pray you have me
excused.
and another said, I have bought five yoke of oxen, I must go to examine them.
I pray you have me excused.
And another said, I have married a wife,
and therefore I cannot come.
So the servant came and reported this to his master.
Then the householder, in anger, said to his servant,
Go out quickly to the streets and lanes of the city,
and bring in the poor and maimed and blind and lame.
And the servant said, Sir, what you have commanded has been done, and there is still room.
And the master said to the servant, Go out to the highways and hedges,
and compel people to come in, that my house may be filled.
For I tell you, none of those men who are invited shall taste my bad.
Thank you.
For many are called, but few are chosen.
Peace be with you, proclaims the gospel, and with all the people.
Oh, Lord, be the Lord.
I'm sorry.
All the boys are waiting for you outside.
All the boys are sitting right here.
First row.
.
I'm waiting.
All of you, all the altar boys.
I have never seen that many.
Good morning.
Why are you here?
To praise Jesus.
What's your name?
It's okay.
Thank you.
What does that mean?
No.
I disagree with you.
I don't know who's talking.
Okay.
No.
You have to go into the room.
Why are you here today?
To serve.
To serve what?
God.
How are you serving God?
Tell me how you're serving God today.
What does that mean?
That's what?
That's a good question.
Okay.
Well, you got some work to do at home too then.
Are you behaving?
You behaving?
You need a haircut?
Not yet.
Okay.
All right.
Well, you're here because it's Sunday and something else is happening.
What else is...
happening now? What are we getting ready for?
Who?
Christmas, the birth of Christ.
And what's going to happen on the birth of Christ?
What are you going to do?
How are you going to celebrate it?
Your family's coming over.
So, do you know the church is like a family?
Can we all come over to your house?
Give the address, everybody.
knows? No? You don't have that much food, huh? Okay. Well, it's an important issue to remember
that we're celebrating. I want to see how the kids are understanding this.
Now, I have a different question for the young people, too. What happens at Christmas?
What happens at Christmas? What are you going to do with the family? Feast. What else?
A gift for the presents.
Presents.
Oh my goodness, we're giving presents now.
Wow.
And let's see.
What would you prefer?
What kind of present do you want for Christmas?
I don't know.
You don't know.
What do you want for Christmas?
A lapar.
A lot.
Top, you said?
What do you want?
You don't know.
What do you want for Christmas?
Well, you're going to buy presents for people.
What are you going to get for mom and dad?
Are you going to get mom, who's going to get mom
a $1 gift card at Starbucks?
No, you aren't.
Don't even tell me you are.
You know you're not going to do that.
What are you going to do?
For mom and dad, you're going to do something more
or from what you want.
have. All of us do that. We do that, we look at who the person is
and we will give something something, but it's with the
how much importance they are in our lives. That's how we end up doing that.
Okay? So do you want a one dollar Starbucks gift card? Would you prefer an
I'm an iPad.
Oh, you'd prefer an iPad.
What's the difference in cost?
A lot.
Let's see.
What are you going to give mommy and daddy for Christmas?
What do you think?
Chocolates?
No chocolates?
What are you going to give them?
What do you want them to give you?
You don't know yet.
Do you want a $1 gift certificate at Starbucks?
I don't think so.
Okay.
Why am I saying this?
Because I want us to recognize that in particular at this season,
we begin to return by graciousness, by means of the gift,
something to the people who have made a difference in our lives.
That's what we do.
You have a brother?
What are you going to give your brother?
Nothing?
Your love?
Okay, well, love is a good object, a good thing.
I want you to understand that.
We measure people.
Where are the Ahi brothers?
I don't see you.
Where are you?
hey
are you? Stand up. Okay. What are you going to give the family for Christmas? Jewelry?
Do you think you can find some jewelry? You know where to buy it? Do you guys get a discount?
The point is, you're not going to give them a $1 Starbucks gift certificate. Correct?
Correct?
OK.
I'm saying this because at this season,
people who have made a difference in our lives
don't always know they've done that.
They won't know it.
But they'll know it when you do something special for them.
And that's important for us to recognize.
Somebody has made a difference in your life.
It could be your parents.
It could be this week your aunt, your uncle,
your brother, your sister.
it could be a teacher
It could be the priest.
And I don't think for any of those,
you're going to give them a $1 Starbucks gift certificate.
I think that's out of the question.
You're going to find something that measures to the reality
of how that impacts my life.
That's what you're going to look at for these people.
And it's important.
But why am I saying that?
because the question then becomes...
comes, I hear a noise, what will you offer to the church that makes a difference in your life?
Sometimes we think, you know, I grew up many years ago, okay? I'm over 40, just so you know.
I'm about 70 now.
so we're not saying anything.
But when we grew up,
our people, in particular from Greece,
when they'd come to the church,
they were used to giving a dollar.
But why?
Because in Greece,
everything was paid for the church by the government.
So that's one of the reasons why they did it that way.
They didn't see that it was just something extra.
But here, it's not a government payout.
Okay?
It doesn't work that way.
way. And what I want you to look at and to consider, just as you would give gifts to people
who have made a difference in your life, consider giving a gift, for example,
to the church for special needs, to help feed the hungry. You may not realize it,
but there are hungry people in this parish, and Father is the one who knows who they are,
and he's...
the one who helps bring them their food. He doesn't advertise it because they don't want that sense.
They don't want the sense for people to think that they can't take care of themselves.
It's a hard issue. So we're preparing for the gift of Jesus coming to us at Christmas to make a
difference. He makes a difference in our lives. But we have to reflect then. We have to respond
in measure to what he does.
for us. Let us do something for the church. Maybe you're seeing all those ads on TV now.
How many of you have seen the St. Jude ads? Okay. Well, I'm a cancer patient too, so I give something
to St. Jude's too, because it makes sense to me. Okay. I grew up helping the Red Cross,
because that made sense to me.
We have to see, we have to measure.
We have to do something as we would do for our own family,
in particular for the church,
to make sure that everything is going to be able to work well.
And you know even for the metropolis,
so that you're clear, even this year,
who went to visit the patriarch?
You know who went to visit the patriarch this year
in Constantinople in Istanbul?
The Pope.
and how did the patriarchate cover the expenses?
The metropolises each had to send $35,000
to make sure that they had the funds to cover.
So we are all in a process and in a period of giving.
And at this time when we're all thinking
and the kids are wondering what they're going to get,
and I'm telling you, you're not getting an iPad.
Maybe you are.
I don't know.
But when we're thinking of what are we going to give our children,
and we're getting big special things for them,
and for our families, and do something also for God.
Something for the church.
What is that?
This akusa?
Okay.
She's figuring out what she's doing.
So we're leaving it there.
but all of us as we measure other people
and in contrast give accordingly.
Measure for that baby who's sitting in the manger
waiting for us to come,
who lived and survived and came ultimately to give his life
so that we might live.
And that's what the story of Christmas is about.
it's the gift of God to us
so that we, in the long run, will live
by having Jesus who gave his life on the cross
a number of years later.
So, I don't know what you want for Christmas.
Do you know what you want for Christmas?
No?
Do you want a $1 Starbucks gift card?
No, okay.
So we know.
He doesn't want a $1 Starbucks gift card.
Family's gonna do something good for him.
We know.
that but all of us have to remember that we are a family and that together we have to look out for
each other we have to help those who are in need we have to help those who don't can't say that
they're in need but we can help them through father to make sure that this family as a community
is well, is arm in arm together
for the work and the glory of God.
You know what you're going to say at Christmas?
Christ is born.
And how will you respond?
Father Michael?
Christ is born.
We didn't hear you.
Glorify him.
Christ is born.
Again, Christ is born.
Glorify him.
That's what we have to do, and we do it by our actions.
We do it by our faith.
We do it by our love.
Christ is born.
Amen.
Inside, all the boys, get ready.
Oh, do I need this?
Oh, yeah.
Almost.
If you want to.
All right.
Come on.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
I know.
I can't believe
Oh, God.
Субтитры создавал DimaTorzok
I'm sorry.
Amen.
Συμήθως, εμείς ομήθως, ο Θεός, η δη βασιλεία του.
Ωντυς Αγγίλων,
γύρω
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Συνήθως, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός,
ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Apo'cum mensa, apo'cum mensa.
Let me
Amen.
Asa Mary.
O St. Basilea,
O Lugum,
All right.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
May the Lord our God
remember us all in his kingdom
both now and forever.
and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
May the Lord our God
remember your archpriesthood
in his kingdom
always now and forever
and unto the ages of ages.
Amen.
For the members of the parish council,
and the members of the parish council,
Thank you.
Αμήν.
Amen.
Της άρχης αιροσύνης ολίς δη βασιλεία αιώστηκε ο Θεός,
Ouratos,
Noi corummemor,
Acesi,
Acesi.
Alleluia, Alleluia
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Υπέρ των πρωτεθέντων τιμιών δώρων του Κύριου δε ηθόμεν,
Κύριε ελεησόν,
υπέρ του Αγίου οικού του, του και των μεταπίστεως ευλαβίας
και φόβου Θεού ισιόντων εν αυτόν του Κύριου δε ηθόμεν,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Υπερ του ρηστιναι ημάς ο φοπάσις θλίψεως, οργείς κινδύνου κι ανάγκης του Κυρίου δε ηθόμες.
Αν τη λαβού σώσον, ελέησον και διαφύλαξον ημάς, ο Θεός της ηχάρητης.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
That the whole day may be perfect,
only peaceful and sinless,
let us ask the Lord.
And this, O Lord,
for an angel of peace, a faithful guide,
a guardian of our souls and bodies,
let us ask the Lord.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
For pardon and remission of our sins and transgressions, let us ask the Lord.
For that which is good and beneficial for our souls and for peace for the world, let us ask the Lord.
From this storm
That we may complete the remaining time of our life in peace and repentance.
Let us ask the Lord.
Bend this, O Lord.
And let us ask for a Christian into our life, peaceful without shame and suffering.
For a good defense before the awesome judgment seat of Christ.
And this
Oh Lord.
Commemorating our most holy, pure, blessed, and glorious Lady, the Theodopos and Ever, Virgin Mary,
together with all the saints, let us commend ourselves to one another in a full life through Christ our God.
Glory to you, O Lord.
To the mercies of the Holy God and Son, with whom you are blessed, together with your own
Let us pray in spirit, not forever, to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Give us the sweetest spirit, the whole part of the Lord.
Let you, Lord, let my tears be sure.
Let us love one another
That with oneness of mind we may
and that
I believe in one God, Father Almighty, creator of heaven and earth, and of all things visible.
and invisible. And in one
Lord Jesus Christ, the only
begotten Son of God, begotten
of the Father before all ages.
Light of light, true
God of true God, begotten
and not created, of one essence
with the Father, through whom
all things were made.
Who for us men and for our salvation
came down from heaven
and was incarnate of the
Holy Spirit and the Virgin
Mary and became man.
He was crucified.
under Pontius Pilate, and suffered and was buried, and he rose on the third day according
to his scriptures.
He ascended into heaven, and he seated at the right hand of the Father, and he will come
again with glory to judge the living and the dead, his kingdom shall have no end.
And in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the Creator of life, who proceeds from the Father, who
together with the Father and the Son is worshipped and glorified, who spoke to the prophet,
and the holy Catholic and the soul of church.
I confess one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.
I look for the resurrection of the dead
and the life of the age to come. Amen.
Let us stand aright.
Let us stand in awe.
Let us be attentive
that we may present the holy offering in peace.
I'm here.
The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ
and the love of God the Father
and the communion of the Holy Spirit
be with all of you.
And with your spirit
A los jóvenes das cardías.
Let all make cross on Kyrgyi, Lord.
Let us give thanks to the Lord.
It is proper and right.
Singing the triumphal hymn,
exclaiming, proclaiming,
Thank you.
sing
Holy, Holy,
Holy
Lord
Evangelicals
Evident
are filled
with your
glory
Hosanna
in the
Oh
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.
Hosanna in the highest.
Oh
Take it, this is my body which is broken for you for the remission of sins.
Amen.
Drink of this all of you.
This is my blood of the new covenant which is shed for you and for many for the remission of sins.
Wow.
The sight, consoled, your own of your own, we offer to you in all and for all.
Once you remember this spiritual worship,
Father, we are in the midst of the great and the great
and the great and the great and the great and the great
and that which is in this cup of Christ
changing them by your Holy Spirit
so that they may be most particular
in the kingdom of heaven
all of us
sing
where the body stood
and the happy righteous spirit
I am here.
Amém.
especially for our most holy, pure, blessed, and glorious Lady of Theodokos and ever-Virgin Mary.
Holy it is right to call you blessed, and we bless you of Theodokos.
May them who are ever blessed
You have known no way, You are truly the mother of our God.
Higher still in honor than the cherubim, And you are beyond the empire,
Far more glorious than the seraphim.
You without corruption have given birth unto God the Word.
Truly theodocus, you do we magnify.
I...
Among the first, remember, Lord, our holy and ecumenical patriarch, Bartholomew.
Grant unto your holy churches in peace, safety, honor, and health,
unto length of days, rightly teaching the word of your truth.
Above all, remember, Lord, our Father in Metropolitan Nicholas.
Grant that he may serve your holy churches in peace.
Keep him safe, honorable, and healthy for many years,
rightly teaching the word of your truth.
and remember each one
of us those whom we call to mind
and all the people.
And all
your people.
And grant them with one voice and one
heart we may glorify and praise your most honorable
and majestic name of the Father
and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit
now and forever and through the ages of
ages.
Amen.
To the mercies of our great God
and Savior Jesus Christ
Be
with all of you
and with your
spirits.
Having commemorated all the saints
again and again in peace, let us pray to the Lord.
Give them a song.
For the precious gifts you present
and consecrated, let us pray to the Lord.
Amen.
that our God who loves mankind and is the superior
and the superior and mystical
all the nations that our God who is here
is the great we see in return
to God upon us in God's grace
and let our God
and our God
having asked for the unity of the faith
and for the communion of the Holy Spirit
let us commend ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ
our God
to you
Oh, oh.
Καί καταξιώσον ημάς δέσποτα με τα παρησία σαν κατακρήτος,
τολμάν επικαλείστεσαι τόν επουράνιον θεόν, πατέρα, και λέγει.
Πατερημόν, ο εμπίς ουρανής, αγιαστείτε το όνομά σου,
ελθέτε ο εγκρασιλίας σου, γεννηθείτε το θερμά σου,
ως εγρανό και εμπιθυσκή.
Τον άρθο νημών των επιουσιών, δώσιν ειν σύνταρον, και άφεσιν ειν τα οφενήματα νημών,
ως και εμείς αφίε με τις οφηλέτες νημών, και εμείς ελέγγυσι μας ως ποιοσμόν, αλλά ελίσαι ειμάς από το τον υλού.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
With thine is the kingdom, the power, and the glory of the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
O'er tu ne m'artissu
T'as ke falassim on tu Kyri o klinome
Si Kyrie
By the grace, mercy, and love for us of your only begotten Son with whom you are blessed
Together with your all holy good and life-giving Spirit
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen
Proscomen
Let us be
Attentive
The holy
gifts for the holy people
of God
Amen.
Иисус Христа.
Theu at us, Amen.
Amen.
Jesus, Lord.
Christ
who
the glory
of the
Father
Amen
Αγίσθηκα.
i el tinerpida t'hi sentim.
Praise the Lord.
Oh, praise the Lord.
From the heavens
Praise Him in the highest.
Rest, repite.
Thank you.
And his peace
Praise the Lord
Amen.
Praise the Lord from the heavens.
Praise Him in the high.
Thank you.
Praise the Lord.
O praise the Lord.
From the heavens praise.
In the highest
I am the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the
Econura nos, fegnite,
of God
and peace
in sea
Praise the Lord.
O praise the Lord from the heavens.
Praise Him in the heart.
Metaphobus, theopisteus, chegapis, prosentete
With the fear of God, with faith, and with love drawn ears.
Thank you.
Thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, thee, the
you
Grazie a tutti.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
ПЕСНЯ
And diva si tria su.
I sit in my hand.
And did I see the fear of our souls?
We see you
O Son of God, and partaker of your mystical Son of earth.
Thank you.
For I will not keep of your mysteries
to your enemies.
Will I give you a kiss as if you do?
God like God, we will I confess you.
Remember me, O Lord, in your kingdom.
Remember me, O Master, in your kingdom.
Remember me, O Holy One, in your kingdom.
The Circle of Life.
In the name of the Lord,
the Lord is the Son of God.
Thank you.
Om istilion di pot,
U frilima silvoso,
The life of tomorrow.
Oh
Nishtiti Mugiliet, enti vasi lia su.
Be safe.
Oh
En divasi liga azul.
Gracias.
Save, O God, your people, and bless your inheritance.
Субтитры создавал DimaTorzok
me.
Arise,
having partaken of the divine,
holy, pure, mortal,
heavenly life, creating an awesome
mysteries of Christ. Let us
worthily give thanks unto the Lord.
We're
creation.
Help us,
save us, have mercy upon us,
and keep us, O God, by your grace.
Lord,
have mercy.
Having prayed for a perfect, holy, peaceful, and sinless day,
let us commend ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
To you, O Lord.
For you are a sanctification, and to you we give glory
to the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Κύριε λέεισαν, Κύριε λέεισαν, Κύριε λέεισαν, δε σου οτάδει ευλογήσαν.
Οι ευλογών τους ευλογούντας σε Κυρία και αγιάζον τους επισήπε πειθώτας, σώσουν τον λαό σου και ευλόγησαν την κληρονομία σου, το πλήρωμα της εκκλησίας σου φύλαξον αγιά σου, προσγαπώντας την επρέπεια του οίκου σου,
Σε άπτωσαν οι δόξες, όμπι δέχει.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Amen.
.
How many altar boys do we have?
Now it's 15.
The other day it was 14.
Can anybody just walk and serve at the altar?
No.
Thank you.
Who said that?
Up here.
Who are you?
Alexander Kinsora.
Okay.
The answer you gave is correct.
Anybody cannot just walk in the altar.
People think, well, they're a man, they can walk in.
No.
Well, theoretically, technically you have to
have to have a blessing. And what we're doing today is giving these young men the blessing
to be altar servers.
So we haven't done it for a few years.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10,
11, 12, 14, 15.
So somebody ain't getting a document
today. I don't know who that's going to be.
But let's have a prayer.
O Lord, Almighty God, you who are the one who gives the breath of life to all and sustains
all of creation, accept these your servants.
Nicholas, Nicolaus, Vasilius, Athanasius, Petrus, Gabriel, Michael, Demetrius, Aristides, Theophanes, Theophanes, Phimostenes, Nicolaus, Alexandros, Sables,
and who are prepared to serve your Holy Church and the place where your glory abides.
Sanctify them and grant them to study and to read your sacred words with all wisdom and knowledge,
preserving them in a pure manner of life.
enable them to serve you in irreproachable and blatant manner.
and purity of life and heart,
and make him worthy to receive the reward of those who love the beauty of your church.
For you are God, our holy, and to you we offer glory to the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
I guess we have a chef here.
Nicholas Cooksey.
Thank you.
One by one, you'll come on up.
All yours.
You can put that up.
Put that up.
And I can't help.
No, fix it.
Make it straight.
Yeah, that's a little crooked, but turn around.
Axios.
Okay.
Come on up.
One step up.
loss.
In the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, amen.
The servant of God, I callos, this time to an accolade and a reader in God's holy Orthodox Church.
Axios! Axios!
Massilius Petter! I don't know where Mr. Petter is.
Up one step.
Amen.
and a senior since time to an acolyte and a reader.
God's holy reference to that scripture.
In the name of the Father, Son of the Holy Spirit, amen.
Actios!
Okay.
After you put it on, stand up.
Okay?
Athanasios, don't ask all.
Yes.
One step up.
In the name of the Father, Son of the Holy Spirit.
The servant of God, Athanasios, is time to an acolyte and a reader.
I'm gonna get you guys holding up.
In the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Axios! Axios!
Petrus Cole.
One up, one step.
In the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
The servant of God, Petrus, is touched.
An acolyte and a reader of God's holyness in the next church.
In the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Axios! Axios!
I thought that's yours.
Gabriel Gomez, Paul.
Uh-huh.
You got it.
Okay, not the stuff.
In the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.
Amen.
The servant of God, Gabriel, his timesman, an acolyte, and a reader of God's holy work of
the next church.
In the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Axios.
Michael Melvin.
Is there a Melvin family?
Do I know him?
How do you know him?
Do you know him?
I never heard of Louis Mello.
Is he here?
Where is he?
I didn't see him.
Okay.
With a bald head, you said?
Oh, you're in trouble.
In the name of the Father,
come up, folks.
Holy Spirit,
sir, I've got my God.
This time is an accolade and a reader of God's Holy Orthodox Church.
In the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, I am.
Axios!
Okay, Michael, now.
You need that.
Thank you.
In the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, I am.
The Sermon of God Beneath This is time to an acolyte and a reader of God's
Orthodox Church, in the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. Amen.
Axios! Axios!
Here we go.
Ades-tevis Mosquidis.
Oh, well.
Now he's here.
In the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. Amen.
The servant of God.
Ades-tevis, it's time to be an acolyte and leader in God's Holy Orthodox Church,
in the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. Amen.
Amen.
Axios!
The name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
The servant of God, Theophilus, is time to have an acolyte and a reader in God's holy Orthodox Church.
In the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Axios!
The Ophanis Papaclos Andini.
Are you a papa?
Not yet?
Okay, your papu's a papa.
Where's your papu a papa?
In the garden.
Okay, amen.
The servant of God,
theophilus, in the name of the Father,
Son, and Holy Spirit, amen.
The servant of God, theophilus,
is the time to an acolyte and a reader
in God's holy Orthodox Church
in the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, amen.
Axios!
We must have this.
take us. Oh, we hear it.
Come on up.
Come on up. In the name of the Father,
the Holy Spirit, amen.
The servant of God will stand. It's time to
be an accolade and a reader of God's Holy
Orthodox Church. In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit, amen.
Axios!
Careful, careful. That's long.
Careful. No trip. Careful.
You're not watching. Pick up.
You're on a trip.
and have a drink.
Nicolaus Tanassas
In the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, Amen.
The Sermon of God, Nicolaus.
It's time to an acolyte and a reader.
In God's hope we are for the next church.
In the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, Amen.
Axios! Axios!
Alexandros Vader.
Is Darth here?
No?
He's here? Darth is here? Where's Darth?
Okay.
In the name of the Father,
Son, and Holy Spirit, Amen.
The servant of God,
an accolade,
in God's Holy Orthodox Church,
in the name of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit,
Amen.
Axios!
Savas!
Where is the Savas?
Not here.
Now, then, guess what?
here. Come on up here, Mrs. Zingas.
Are the
Zingas's here?
Yes. Yeah? Okay.
In the name of the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Now, sir, then God's Sabbath, it's time to
be an accolade and a reader in God's holy
and a church. In the name of the Father,
and the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Axios!
Are we all set?
Guys, put your robes down.
here and take a picture.
Make sure you can be seen.
Father Michael, can you be seen?
Okay. Look and smile. Yay!
Yay!
Okay.
AXIE, AXIE, AXIE
Worthy, worthy, worthy, worthy, worthy
They are worthy
AXE
God bless, congratulations to the families.
The families, if you want to come up real quick for a picture, you can do that too.
If you want to be in the picture with the kids.
If you don't, that's fine, but come on up.
There's a bold man that wants to come up here.
I'm waiting for you.
Come on, man.
Come on!
I don't know, you figured out with the camera people
where you going.
Camera people, tell them where they're going.
Someone's got a shiny head, where is he?
I can move forward.
One step forward.
Oh.
Standing on a chair, I know nothing.
All set? You got them?
Congratulations.
Now, question for you.
What do you need to run the church?
You need a priest?
you need
God. Well, God's why we're here. And then what do you need?
A year. Okay.
So the church runs on a year and God.
You need a priest? That's my point.
You need a priest. Oh, you need
a chanter, too. Oh, you need a chanter. I don't know about that one,
but you got a priest. You got some chanters.
and I heard there's some
Nick Chanter over here.
Where is he?
Related to the priest.
I didn't see him.
Where is he?
Nicola.
Nicola, Nicola.
Puisse Nicola.
Then the psalis cimmeron.
Then acume dipotas.
You're not singing it.
I don't know.
Come on, come on up here, Nicole.
Why are you coming over here?
I'm selling you.
Come on over here.
You're not missing it.
I want you right there.
Why not?
What did you get your hair cut to?
I'm from New York.
I can talk like this.
Okay.
What do I need to know?
How long have you been chanting?
How many years?
25 years a chanter.
And you know there are ranks of chanters.
You didn't know that.
But what I want to do with all of you...
Turn around.
Stand up straight, very well.
Shall we proclaim him a Proto Psalti?
Say it.
I can hear you.
Yes.
The Proto Psalti is the Senorias of the Metropolitan Detroit.
Congratulations.
Axios, axios.
Any family here?
Stand right here.
Worthy, worthy.
Family, come on up.
He is worthy.
Axios.
Okay, come on this side too.
So we'll sit in the middle.
We got you.
Okay, I'll set.
Hold on.
Everybody set.
Okay.
Congratulations.
That's it.
Give him a hug.
Daddy, give him a spanking.
Father Michael, you got the book with the saints today?
Father Michael is coming on the other side.
Amen.
the Holy Spirit, the All-Immaculate Holy Mother,
the power of the precious and life-giving cross,
the protection of the body,
the body of the powers of heaven,
the supplications of the Holy Glorious Prophet,
and the Father of John the Baptist,
the Holy Glorious and Praiseworthy Apostles,
the Holy Glorious and Trent,
the martyrs of our righteous and God-bearing fathers,
of Padre Dieu, whose glorious church is dedicated,
and our Father and Saint John Christus,
the Archbishop of Constantinople,
of the Holy and Righteousness of the Lord,
the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord,
and the Lord, the Lord, and the Lord,
and the Lord, and the Lord, and the Lord,
left, heels, heels.
Υπησανήμικος, Φιλήμων, Απολώνιος, Υπάθιος,
Άνια, Νομάρους, που θέλουν να γνωρίσουμε
και να γνωρίσουμε σήμερα.
Είτε όλοι οι στρατιώσεις,
χρήμαστε να μας παρακολουθούν.
Θα μας παρακολουθούν.
Ευχαριστώ που είσαι.
May we have the passing of our trays at this time?
The first tray is for our stewardship contributions
or general donations to the church.
The second tray is for our iconography fund.
I want the first tray first.
This is for...
14 carats.
I love it.
Thank you.
I don't know where this is.
Good morning, everybody.
Good morning.
Your Eminence, Metropolitan, Nicholas, Reverend Fathers, Michael Verlamos and Michael Manos.
Nico, would you please come here?
We were planning to do this some other time, but the occasion is really appropriate.
First of all, on behalf of the choir, we want to congratulate you.
for this prestigious honor that you received today.
You are truly worthy.
You're one of my kids.
I saw you.
I watched you grow up in the church.
But you agreed to be or you chose to be our choir director two years ago.
Looking forward, we don't know what's ahead of us from second to second.
But with the trust of faith in God and his guidance,
and that if you are a leader, we will continue.
to accomplish what God planned for our choir.
On behalf of our choir, I have this presentation for you.
One is a lapel pin of Saint Mectarios,
which is the patron saint of music and choir
of the Greek Orthodox Church.
15 years ago, 1500 years ago,
he composed the Kandakia that we sing to this day.
and one of the most beautiful and recognizable
recognizable ones we sang today,
Iparthenos simonum.
The virgin comes today to the cave to give birth.
In addition, we give you a gift certificate
to the restaurant Pegasus that you enjoy with your family.
No, wait.
May the choir please stand,
because this presentation is not because of me.
The choir, the entire choir,
an old hymn.
words of an old hymn express our sentiments for you. May the Lord bless and
keep you. May the Lord shine his face upon you and be gracious unto you. May the
Lord turn his face towards you with favor and grant you peace. We wish you
and your family a blessed Merry Christmas and a safe and Happy New Year.
We love you.
Bravo!
I think now would be a good time to make the announcements before we dismiss.
Just please note that tomorrow evening at 5 p.m. in our cultural center,
our Greek school will be having their annual Christmas program.
Again, tomorrow evening at 5, and the whole parish is invited to attend.
On Tuesday evening, we...
7 p.m. we have our last Orthodox Life session for the month of December. We'll reconvene again in
January. There is no Greek school this coming Wednesday, but there will be a choir and chant
rehearsal this Wednesday at 6.30 p.m. Our council meeting at 6.30 p.m. on Thursday. Friday evening
at 6.30. We have our Goya making, preparing the baskets that we deliver to our homes.
homebound parishioners. And we have 80 homebound parishioners. So our Goyans are going to be
working hard Friday evening. And for those of you who have volunteered to help make these deliveries,
it'll be this coming Saturday from 10 in the morning till 2. You can pick up one of these
Christmas baskets and deliver it to one of our homebound parishioners. That will be from 10
in the morning.
morning until 2 in the afternoon. And then if you're not able to do it on Saturday, we'll do it
on Sunday after church to pick up a basket and to please deliver it to one of our homebound
parishioners. Vai Hadji Kosti has the list, and I'm sure Olga has a copy of it in the office.
So that's next Saturday and Sunday.
On Saturday morning...
our annual Divine Liturgy at the Ahepa Apartments in Harrison Township will take place.
And again, everyone is invited and welcome to attend that. And then next Sunday is our Sunday
School Christmas pageant. So we will ask all our Sunday School parents, when you arrive at church,
and hopefully it's at 10 o'clock in the morning, that the students dismiss directly into Sunday
school so that they can have time.
to rehearse before the pageant, which will begin after liturgy next Sunday.
I believe those are all the announcements.
Without certainly forgetting the most important announcement
is to welcome His Eminence Metropolitan Nicholas
and thanking him for his visitation and presiding over the Divine Liturgy.
your Eminence, you have this ability.
it's uncommon.
In a sense
in a sense
you always make
our own home feel like home.
And I always appreciate
your love and your service
in the altar.
All you do for the youth
of our community
and certainly for the clergy
of our community as well.
your prayers, your prayers.
are always in our prayers here in the altar and certainly in the nave. So, Your Eminence,
we wish you only the very best Christmas and a blessed, happy, and healthy new year.
Thank you, Your Eminence. And then also, we can't forget Deacon Stephen who comes and assists
His Eminence. It's always a pleasure and joy to have him in our midst. Our altar boys,
all of our altar boys, we have 34 altar boys, 15 of which were Tantra.
today, and this is something that I have been remiss in doing. The last time we tonsured
altar boys was in 2012. Yes, I know. It's been a long time, but we did plan, to be fair.
13 years ago.
Yes, we were planning in 2020, but then COVID happened and everything got pushed back, but
I'm not here to make excuses, but this is a tradition we like to make annual. Whenever
his Eminence visits our parish we'd like to have a new cohort of alterations.
boys. And I recently learned that we also are tonsuring young ladies as readers as well.
So some of the phenomenal readers we've heard lately are girls from our parish.
We're keeping a list. We're checking it twice. And I'm sure everyone's going to be nice on that list.
And we will record these names. And then the next time His Eminence comes, we'll not only
Tantra, our altar boys, but also...
also our girl readers.
And for the distinction,
Nico, congratulations.
Always worthy of this.
We should have done this when you were six years old.
Truly worthy. God bless you.
What's that?
He's only seven.
Again, Your Eminence, thank you again for your presence,
for your prayers and your visitation.
with us. God bless all of you for the families of our altar boys and our choir. We have an
appreciation luncheon that's taking place in the hall. And then the coffee hour will be available
in our fellowship hall. But in the foyer, we have a luncheon appreciation brunch for our choir
and for our altar boys and their families. That is our tantra altar boys. So God bless and keep
you. We look forward to seeing you all, if not during this week.
uh certainly next sunday god bless you all i've read you got a church in you ain't doing a church
a what a church oh yes yes
you better do the church
So His Eminence always advocates, everybody comes to church and stays in church for memorials,
trisayun, for the dead. We rarely are in church to witness the 40-day blessing of a mother and
a child, our newest mother and child. So it's appropriate that you are all here. I know this
has been a very long Sunday already for all of you, but it's certainly worth it. So we are blessed
you
to have the 40-day blessing of Father Tom and Perezvitara Denise Michalos' grandson,
or I should say Sotiri and Nikki Michalos' new firstborn son.
So today is the 40-day blessing, and we're all here to witness and to pray for mother and child.
So may we all please rise.
Amen.
Now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord have mercy.
O Lord God almighty, Father of our Lord Jesus Christ,
by your word.
has made every rational and irrational creation
that brought all things that have nothingness into being.
We pray to you and implore you
to cleanse this, your servant, Niki,
whom by your will you have preserved
and who now comes into your holy church
from every transgression
so that she may be accounted worthy to partake
of your holy mysteries without condemnation.
Bless also this child
which has been born of her.
Increase it, sanctify it, give it understanding
and it prudent and virtuous.
mind for you alone have brought it into being and have shown him the light which bodily sense
perceived so that he might be accounted worthy also of the ideal light and be numbered with
your holy flock through your only begotten son with whom you are blessed together with your all
holy good in life giving spirit now and forever and to the ages of ages
Amen
Let us pray to the Lord
Lord have mercy
O Lord our God
whoever draws near for this
of the human race, come also to this year's servant, Nikki,
through the prayers of your venerable priesthood
and a counter worthy to find refuge
in your holy Catholic Church,
to obtain entrance into the temple of your glory
and worthy also to partake
of the precious body and blood of your Christ.
In the fulfillment of the 40 days,
wash away from her every transgression,
voluntary and involuntary,
so that a counter worthy to enter your holy temple,
she may glorify with us your all holy name.
of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
O Lord, our God, who on the fortieth day
was brought as a child into the temple of the law
by Mary the Virgin Bride and your holy mother
and was carried in the arms of the righteous Simeon,
do you also, sovereign Master, all-powerful,
bless this presented child
that it may appear before you.
the creator of all things.
And do you increase in him every good work acceptable to you,
removing far from him every opposing might
by the sign and likeness of your cross?
For you are he who guards infants, O Lord,
so that a counted worthy of holy baptism
he may obtain the portion of your elect of the kingdom,
being protected with us by the grace of the all-holy
and undivided Trinity.
For unto you we send up glory, honor, and worship
with your eternal Father in your...
all holy good in life giving spirit
now and forever
and to the ages of ages
Amen
The servant of God, Athanassios Kostantinos, is brought into the church in the name of the
Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit. Amen. The servant of God, Athanasios Costadinos,
is brought into the church in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
He flashed quite a smile inside the altar.
Hello.
Congratulations.
He looks just like your father-in-law.
I'll take a photo.
Can I take a photo?
Okay, no.
Photography.
Photographia? Yes.
Watch your step.
Let it be.
I'm American also.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Okay, altar boys.
You can, yeah, it's coming.
All blessings.
Oh, my God.
Αλληλούια.
Εις τοπον πλώης εκεί με κάτε σκηνώστε, επίδατος σαν απαυστεώς ξεχρεύστε με.
Αλληλούια, η ψυχή μου έστρεψε, οδηγήσέ με,
Επιτρίβους δικαιωσύν
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Η ράβδο σου και η βακτηρία σου, αυτέ με παρεκάλεσαν.
Αλληλούια.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Ελυπάνας, ενελέω την κεφαλή μου και το ποτηρίον σου.
Με φύσκω
ο μεωσι.
Bless you.
Thank you.
Obrigado.
Gracias.